<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://curiousstuff.eu/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Improve your sound and Enable Noise cancellation in Ubuntu</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/improve-your-sound-and-enable-noise-cancellation-in-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/improve-your-sound-and-enable-noise-cancellation-in-ubuntu/</guid><description>There is a hidden feature in Ubuntu which will allow you to enable noise cancellation and enhance quality of your online conversations. Here is a short tutorial on how to do it.
Create a backup First, backup of the important stuff.
1 sudo cp /etc/pulse/default.pa /etc/pulse/default.pa.bak Edit your configuration file Now edit default.pa file manually by entering following
1 sudo vi /etc/pulse/default.pa Now, at the end of the file add following configuration</description></item><item><title>Expose the Raspberry Pi to Internet with Cloudflare</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/expose-the-raspberry-pi-to-internet-with-cloudflare/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/expose-the-raspberry-pi-to-internet-with-cloudflare/</guid><description>Many of us who have a Raspberry Pi want to have access to it even from outside our network. Some use it to publish their blog or personal web page, others want to access a torrent server from which they can add downloads when they are not at home so that they are available when they arrive, and for others it could be a gateway to their entire home automation system, being able to control and monitor the status of their home when they are not at home.</description></item><item><title>Installing CUDA Toolkit v11.4.2 on Ubuntu</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/installing-cuda-toolkit-v11.4.2-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/installing-cuda-toolkit-v11.4.2-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>This guide covers the basic instructions needed to install CUDA and verify that a CUDA application can run on Linux.
CUDA on Linux can be installed using an RPM, Debian, Runfile, or Conda package, depending on the platform being installed on.
Installing CUDA Toolkit on Ubuntu When installing CUDA on Ubuntu, you can choose between the Runfile Installer and the Debian Installer. The Runfile Installer is only available as a Local Installer.</description></item></channel></rss>