<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware and electronics on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/categories/electronics/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware and electronics on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://curiousstuff.eu/categories/electronics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Should you care about LEDs usage? Consequences of using them</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/should-you-care-about-leds-usage-consequences-of-using-them/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/should-you-care-about-leds-usage-consequences-of-using-them/</guid><description>Should you care about LEDs usage? Have you ever wondered if you should start using LED lights? And you&amp;rsquo;ve never found the time to find out if they&amp;rsquo;re really worth it. Let me show a couple of examples of the consequences of using LED bulbs or lights in your projects, home or even vehicles.
What a LED light really is A light-emitting diode or LED, is a light source consisting of a semiconductor material with two terminals.</description></item><item><title>How to blink the damn ESP32 built-in led</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/how-to-blink-the-damn-esp32-built-in-led/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/how-to-blink-the-damn-esp32-built-in-led/</guid><description>Requirements Install Arduino IDE. Visit their site for instructions. Add permission to use the serial connection and operate with it. Make sure your board is recognized properly. Add permission for serial operations In case your current user is not added to dialout group, you have to add it.
1 2 sudo adduser $USER dialout sudo usermod -a -G dialout $USER Check if ESP32 board is connected to your computer The fastest way to check whether the board is connected to the computer or not is using lsusb command</description></item></channel></rss>