<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>peer on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/tags/peer/</link><description>Recent content in peer on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://curiousstuff.eu/tags/peer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crawling Ethereum Blockchain for automated Smart Contract Extraction</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/crawling-ethereum-blockchain-for-automated-smart-contract-extraction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/crawling-ethereum-blockchain-for-automated-smart-contract-extraction/</guid><description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how an automated data extraction can be dome for massive data analysis processes. The goal is to download all interesting Blockchain information as a processable file like a CSV. I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you throw the process of making it possible.
Requirements To be able to crawl the Blockchain data, we must have first a ledger peer syncronized and running. If you dont have one, you can check this guide about how to setup one.</description></item><item><title>Running an Ethereum Rinkeby full node in 2022</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/running-an-ethereum-rinkeby-full-node-in-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/running-an-ethereum-rinkeby-full-node-in-2022/</guid><description>What is Rinkeby Testnet Rinkeby is an Ethereum test network that allows for blockchain development testing before deployment on Mainnet, the main Ethereum network.
The Proof-of-Authority test network was established in April 2017. It uses the Clique PoA consensus protocol, and is maintained by the Geth developer team.
The network is supported by Geth, Nethermind and Hyperledger Besu.
Some features of the network are:
Testnet / Live: Test Chain ID: 4 Network ID: 4 Live Since: April 2017 Block time: 15 seconds Consensus / block proposer: PoA – Proof-of-Authority Permissioned: Yes Governance / Authorities: Known developers who sign the blocks Meaning of PoA:</description></item></channel></rss>