<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>performance on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/tags/performance/</link><description>Recent content in performance on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://curiousstuff.eu/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dec2hex: optimizing decimal to hexadecimal conversion algorithms for speed</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/dec2hex-optimizing-decimal-to-hexadecimal-conversion-algorithms-for-speed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/dec2hex-optimizing-decimal-to-hexadecimal-conversion-algorithms-for-speed/</guid><description>Hexadecimal format Hexadecimal is the name of the numbering system that is base 16. This system, therefore, has numerals 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, and 15. That means that two-digit decimal numbers 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, and 15 must be represented by a single numeral to exist in this numbering system. To address the two-digit decimal values, the alphabetic characters A, B, C, D, E, and F are used to represent these values in hexadecimal and are treated as valid numerals.</description></item><item><title>Lightning fast stock market data parsing. Get a boost of 70%</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/lightning-fast-stock-market-data-parsing.-get-a-boost-of-70/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/lightning-fast-stock-market-data-parsing.-get-a-boost-of-70/</guid><description>Con el confinamiento por el Coronavirus y esta situación tan caótica, uno tiene más tiempo para estar delante del ordenador y hacer cosas locas; o frikadas como me gusta llamarlas! Una de ellas es procesar datos de la Bolsa, y como esta es mi primera experiencia con ello, he empezado con la Bolsa española: BME, que es la que más cerca tengo, aunque técnicamente da igual cual elegir porque lo importante son los datos en sí.</description></item><item><title>Detecting a valid IPv4 in Go like a boss</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/detecting-a-valid-ipv4-in-go-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/detecting-a-valid-ipv4-in-go-like-a-boss/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>A short analysis of different alternatives to check IPv4 validity comparing complexity vs performance of their implementations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Benchmarking Go Ethereum account creation in Android</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/benchmarking-go-ethereum-account-creation-in-android/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/benchmarking-go-ethereum-account-creation-in-android/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>How to run native Go code In Android and bench results!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>