<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Random on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/categories/random/</link><description>Recent content in Random on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://curiousstuff.eu/categories/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding EVM: an introduction to Ethereum OPCODES</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/understanding-evm-an-introduction-to-ethereum-opcodes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/understanding-evm-an-introduction-to-ethereum-opcodes/</guid><description>The Ethereum Virtual Machine or EVM The Ethereum Virtual Machine is the software platform that developers can use to create decentralized applications (DApps) on Ethereum. At any given block in the chain, Ethereum has one and only one &amp;lsquo;canonical&amp;rsquo; state, and the EVM is what defines the rules for computing a new valid state from block to block.
The EVM design simplified The EVM behaves as a mathematical function would: Given an input, it produces a deterministic output.</description></item><item><title>Installing Latex and Texmaker in Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/installing-latex-and-texmaker-in-ubuntu-20.04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/installing-latex-and-texmaker-in-ubuntu-20.04/</guid><description>Introducing LaTeX LaTeX is a text composition system, oriented to the creation of written documents with high typographic quality. Due to its characteristics and possibilities, it is used especially intensively in the generation of scientific articles and books that include, among other elements, mathematical expressions.
LaTeX consists of a large set of TeX macros, written by Leslie Lamport in 1984, with the intention of facilitating the use of the typesetting language, TEX, created by Donald Knuth.</description></item><item><title>Go released 1.17</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/go-released-1.17/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/go-released-1.17/</guid><description>Go 1.17 is released The 16 of August 2021, the Go Team releases the version 1.17 of Go
This release brings additional improvements to the compiler, namely a new way of passing function arguments and results. This change has shown about a 5% performance improvement in Go programs and reduction in binary sizes of around 2% for amd64 platforms. Support for more platforms will come in future releases.
Go 1.17 also adds support for the 64-bit ARM architecture on Windows, letting gophers run Go natively on more devices.</description></item><item><title>Easy solution to how to fix CUPS unauthorized error</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/easy-solution-to-how-to-fix-cups-unauthorized-error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/easy-solution-to-how-to-fix-cups-unauthorized-error/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Easy to fix solution to common Ubuntu printing CUPS error:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adios Medium.com, Hola Hugo</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/adios-medium.com-hola-hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/post/adios-medium.com-hola-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Una vez inaugurado oficialmente el blog y migrados los artículos que tenía escritos en
&lt;a href="https://medium.com/" target="_blank">Medium&lt;/a>, es hora de cerrar la cuenta de Medium para siempre (y ejercer mi derecho al olvido) y centrar todos los esfuerzos en este nuevo proyecto.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>