<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Curious Stuff Blog by Sergio Anguita</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://curiousstuff.eu/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/about/</guid><description>Hey, Sergio here, a Cybersecurity Researcher and Blockchain Engineer.
Last known information Current position
Blockchain Security Engineer Very summarized CV Computer Engineering Degree at University of Deusto. DeustoTech Computing Intern. International internship at University of Oulu thanks to Erasmus programme. Recognition of the best final Computer Engineering Degree project. Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Computer Engineering with expertise in Big Data (Hadoop, Spark, Kafka, Flink and Ambari) at University of Deusto. Internship at Iberdrola S.</description></item><item><title>Disqus Comments Policy</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/disqus-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/disqus-policy/</guid><description>First things first: We love comments and appreciate the time that our readers spend to share ideas and give feedback. Thank you to everyone who comments at the Curious Stuff Blog
However, we also want our comments to be as useful as possible to all of our readers. While we keep 99% of comments, we will remove these:
Harassing comments: While conversation and the sharing of different ideas is encouraged, all comments need to be respectful towards our contributors and those leaving comments.</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/license/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/license/</guid><description>This blog is distributed under the Creative Commons - Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International license. This means that you can read the blog on anything you like and wherever you like, keep it with you, give it away to friends and colleagues and even publish it on your websites/blogs. However, you should explicitly mention a link to our original site curiousstuff.eu
No modifications, mixes or other additional creativity may be made with texts or graphics.</description></item><item><title>Premium members</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/premium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/premium/</guid><description>Why should I make a donation? The most common reason to donate is because you found my content useful and helpful for you, no matter what you were looking for.
Why should I get a membership? The most common reason to become a member is because you found my content useful and helpful for you, no matter what you were looking for. Apart from this, premium members are also known to have a series of benefits such as:</description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/archives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://curiousstuff.eu/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curiousstuff.eu/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>